Contact

candynwashington@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ washingtoncandy (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

CPOE

Patient Education
Medical Terminology

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Crisis Prevention Intervention (CPI)
Certified

Basic Life Support (BLS) Certified ANCC Broad Certified Psychiatic Nurse

Certified Mental Health Worker Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS) Certified

Candy N. Washington, MSN, RN-BC

Post-Master's certification at University of South Alabama Birmingham, Alabama Area

Summary

As a Board Certified RN with a Masters degree in Nursing Informatics and 15+years of nursing (acute, ambulatory) and 7 years of Cerner technology implementation experience, articulating healthcare leadership vision, localizing change management strategies, automating clinical practice and EHR operations is what I do best.

My name is Candy Washington and I am an energetic professional, and I have worked as a Cerner Clinical Implementation consultant, Cerner provider and nursing workflow analyst & Trainer as well as a Registered Nurse at UAB. I bring extensive knowledge of inpatient and ambulatory settings, and am truly passionate about improving patient care and quality of life.

I combine industry expertise and high-touch service with immediate action. My success is a product of laser-focused commitment to clinical transformation and process/workflow optimization.

My strengths include:

- ► Using IMPACT to optimize care delivery process; trained Cerner Providers across: Powerchart, Ambulatory, FirstNET, I-View, CareNet, Mpages, CPOE, PowerNote, Dynamic Doc, EMAR, and Command Center.
- ► Extensive Travel Nurse experience across; Cardiac, SICU, PACU, Renal, and Psychiatry Units. Builds rapid rapport with new healthcare teams.
- ► Healthcare workflow, clinical data, and compliance expert: HIPPA/ HITECH, JACHO Standards, Electronic Health Record (EHR), OSHA, DEA/OIG Training & Compliance.

Educational achievements/certifications include:

- ► Master of Science, Nursing Informatics (MSN), Bachelor of Science, Nursing (BSN), Bachelor of Science, Psychology.
- ► Board Certified, Psychiatric/Mental Health Nursing (RN-BC).
- ► Basic Life Support (BLS), Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), Crisis Prevention Intervention (CPI), Certified Mental Health Worker.

I am on LinkedIn to share, learn, and explore new opportunities. I am always open to conversation, so feel free to connect with me, or request a copy of my resume.

□ candynwashington@yahoo.com

Experience

HealthITq Behavioral Health IT Lead July 2019 - Present (1 year)

TrainingWheel, Inc.
6 years 11 months

Healthcare Informatics Consultant
August 2013 - Present (6 years 11 months)

Fort Myers, Florida Area

Cerner Care Coordinator Trainer March 2017 - March 2017 (1 month) Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Trained Care Coordinators' on a new Cerner application known as Cerner HealtheCare and HealtheRegistries.

Cerner Clinical Strategist
October 2016 - January 2017 (4 months)
Baltimore, Maryland Area

Cerner classroom case manager Trainer April 2016 - June 2016 (3 months)

Page 2 of 8

Fort Lauderdale, Florida

Cerner healthcare consultant Cerner consultant August 2013 - Present (6 years 11 months)

Electronic Healthcare Systems
Nursing Informatics Consultant and Trainer
August 2012 - Present (7 years 11 months)
Nationwide

I have implemented Cerner Millennium System technology and delivered atthe-elbow training, nursing and provider informaticist, team lead, command center lead, workflow analysis and a trainer within the US healthcare systems, hospitals, and practices across the United States for the last 6 years.

I work with Clinicians and IT Professionals, refine information systems roadmap, and provide comprehensive training/support across diverse healthcare units.

I am a subject matter expert on Cerner system principles and its correlating roles related to practice/organization transformation, quality improvement, compliance, and administrative efficiencies.

A few key projects/successful implementations include:

- ► Cerner IT consultant/Interim Command Center Leader, Harbor hospital (2017)
- ► Cerner Care Coordinator Trainer, Broward hospital (2017)
- ► Cerner Clinical Strategist, MedStar (2016 2017)
- ► Cerner Case Manager Trainer, Broward Healthcare (2016)
- ► Cerner Provider Trainer, Charleston Area Medical Center (2016)
- ► Clinical Strategist & Advisory Board Member, MedStar Medical Center (2016)
- ► Cerner Training Project, Broward Health Medical Center (2016)

- ► UMASS Migration Project Consultant (2015)
- ► Soarian Financial & Scheduling (Siemens) Consultant (2014)
- ► Cerner Ambulatory-Outpatient, Physician Training & Support (2014)

Each situation and organization is unique, so I emphasize flexibility to maximize productive, best-practice system use.

I enjoy sharing my challenges, accomplishments, and am always open to conversation. For more detailed information on my involvement in these projects, please request my resume.

Currently Seeking New Contract
Nursing Informaticist or Workflow Analyst
August 2012 - Present (7 years 11 months)

The University of Alabama at Birmingham Registered Nurse March 2009 - Present (11 years 4 months)

I am currently working PRN at UAB in the Center for Psychiatric Medicine; I provide evidence-based nursing care, implement and manage care plans and provide behavioral/emotional support for children, adolescents, adults and geriatric patients with mental illness and behavioral problems.

Various travel nurse companies
Travel Registered Nurse
February 2006 - Present (14 years 5 months)
United States

I have extensive experience as a Travel Nurse requiring rapid rapport building with new healthcare teams - I am a strong communicator and build positive new relationships with ease.

I have gained diverse experience on Cardiac Unit, SICU, PACU, Renal (Medical Unit, Stroke Unit, Dialysis) and Psychiatry (Geriatric, Adult, Children, Adolescent) departments. This experience includes:

★ Jackson Nursing Travel Agency; 2007 - 2015

Contracted to multiple cities across the U.S. and worked diverse nursing units: Cardiac, ER Observation and Children and Adolescent Psychiatric Department.

★ St. Vincent's/Staffing Solutions; 2009 -2012

Cared for patients across diverse hospital units including: Cardiac/Telemetry, SICU, PACU, ER Observation, Oncology and Medical-Surgical.

★ Aces Travel Nursing Agency; 2007 - 2012

Contracted to Alta Bates Summit, performed assignments in: Cardiac/ Telemetry, Stroke, Renal Medical-Surgical, Orthopedic and PACU Units.

★ RN, Trinity Medical Center; 2007 - 2010

Ensured optimal patient outcomes and contracted with in-house agency; floated between Cardiac, Pulmonary Medical-Surgical and Psychiatric Units.

★ DCH Health System; 2007 – 2008

Managed patient care within an in-patient Dialysis Unit; administered hemodialysis and peritoneal dialysis and provided education on nutrition, signs of infection, urinary output monitoring and home-use of dialysis machines.

★ Piedmont Hospital; 2006 - 2007

Contracted with Primer Nursing Travel Agency and provided care to patients in the Cardiac Unit; collaborated with teams to develop and implement individualized plans of care.

TEKsystems

Nursing Informatics consultant October 2018 - December 2018 (3 months)

Waterloo, Iowa Area

iMethods

Workflow team lead analyst June 2018 - August 2018 (3 months)

Jacksonville, Florida

Liberty Solutions Workflow Analyst February 2018 - May 2018 (4 months)

Binghamton, New York

TEKsystems

Cerner consultant

November 2017 - November 2017 (1 month)

Waterloo, Iowa

Assisted Providers and Registered Nurses with the hospital's new electronic health record system (Cerner). Provided guidance and training in the ED and a floated to all medical units within the hospital to help with the transition to the new system. Worked with FirstNet, Powerchart, Adhoc, I-view, CareCompass, Dynamic Documentation, MAR, Scanning medications and specimens.

Worked closely with the nurse manager to assist with any workflow and system issues. Assisted with resolving system problems with analysts. Communicated all issues to the Command Center and the resource manager.

Medfirst Consulting Healthcare Staffing Cerner consultant September 2017 - October 2017 (2 months) Mobile, Alabama

Pursuit Healthcare Advisors Cerner Nursing Trainer August 2017 - August 2017 (1 month) Visalia, California Area

Worked with Registered Nurses training Cerner Nursing Module. (Critical Care and Medical Surgery)

The Advisory Board Company 3 months

Team Lead June 2017 - July 2017 (2 months) Baltimore, Maryland

Cerner Dynamic Documentation

Team Lead May 2017 - May 2017 (1 month) Baltimore, Ohio

Cerner Dynamic Documentation

Advisory Broad/TrainingWheel MedConnect (Cerner) Command Center Lead April 2017 - April 2017 (1 month) Baltimore, Maryland Area

Reviewed needs for staffing, Cerner Ticketing intake, ticketing software as well as ticketing resolution and complex ticket escalation. Assisted providers and physician informatics and Nursing informatics with providers workflow.

AP Preferred Solutions Cerner Provider Trainer July 2016 - October 2016 (4 months) Charleston, West Virginia Area

Trained Providers (Physicians, Nurse Practitioners, Physician Assistants) in inpatient setting, assuring correct use of clinical systems and full Cerner EMR adoption; utilized SharePoint and LEAN methodology to identify and rectify resource capability gaps

Baptist Princeton Nursing Informatics Intern 2014 - 2014 (less than a year)

I attained 240 Clinical Hours in 295-bed facility and played a key role in the planning, design, development and implementation of clinical information systems, patient care processes, and training projects.

I assisted with physician elbow support and participated in the following initiatives:

- ★ Implementation of Epic Barcode/scanner and pyxis with RN and Pharmacy staff; I oversaw workflows and execution of configuration changes within applications.
- ★ Supported Epic EHR and led redesign of Unit Clerks and Patient Care.
- ★ Authored CIS/EHR materials and delivered training programs to Unit Clerks and Patient Care Techs across the organization.

Trinity Medical Center
Registered Nurse
April 2007 - November 2012 (5 years 8 months)
Birmingham, Alabama Area

Floated to pulmonary, cardiac floor, medical-surgical unit and psychiatric unit

Princeton Baptist hospital

Registered Nurse

June 2004 - February 2007 (2 years 9 months)

This was my first professional RN employment after completion of Nursing Degree in 2004. I gained hands-on experience and exposure to multidisciplinary team collaboration, models of interventions, medications and calm intervention during crisis situations; served in the Cardiac/Telemetry, SICU and PACU Units.

DCH Health System
Hemodialysis Nurse
December 2002 - June 2003 (7 months)

Tuscaloosa, Alabama Area

Education

University of South Alabama
Post-Master's certification, Psychiatric Mental Health Nurse
Practitioner · (2018 - 2019)

Troy University

Master of Science Nursing (MSN), Nursing Informatics · (2011 - 2014)

The University of Alabama in Huntsville
BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse (2002 - 2004)

University of Alabama at Birmingham
Bachelor's degree, Psychology (1997 - 2000)